We beat anybody in the world and I think
we're going to win next Sunday.
>> Aaron [screaming] jumbled and good jumbo
right handed catch and Chris gets
running.
>> Gino, does it feel like a lifetime ago
that we were talking after you were a
second round pick in 2013 of the Jets?
>> Yeah, man. That was a long time ago,
man. How about that? How about that?
[laughter]
>> Okay, so let's fast forward. When did
this become a reality this off season
that a reunion could be on the horizon?
>> Yeah, I think uh you know, initially
obviously after the season, you know,
there's always going to be some talks,
you know, within the organization
talking about Las Vegas, uh of
potentially what to do and obviously
with the first pick, uh you know,
potential there to go with the
quarterback. And so for me, you know,
obviously that means I I would have some
decisions to make and uh you know, I
really had no idea, you know, where that
could be. Um but once, you know, the
kind of the writing was on the wall, per
se, or you know, once we knew that, you
know, the direction they may be going in
would eventually lead to me heading in a
different direction. Kind of started to,
you know, look look out there and see
what was out there. And you know
eventually you know once uh we were able
to kind of talk to some teams um you
know got word from the uh sorry got word
from the Jets you know that there was a
possibility and uh you know initially
you know I'm the type of guy I just want
to you know hear all the options you
know give me all the options and let me
figure it out and you know once I got
the opportunity um to really like look
at it all um it was kind of a no-brainer
and uh just talking to AG um you know
and hearing his plan for the team and
how he was going to lead it and and what
his plan and my role was with the team.
Uh I was pretty sold on it and then uh
you know Demario Davis hit me with a
text and was like, "Hey man, let's do
it." And uh that was kind of that was
kind of all the you know, confirmation I
needed. So um you know, we we decided to
make it happen. You know, obviously, you
know, very honored, you know, even, you
know, for the team to even, you know,
again, want me to be the quarterback
again. And so I'm looking forward to the
opportunity and extremely excited. My
family's extremely excited to be back in
Form Park. Can you speak to that plan
that AG told you about and what his
vision is for you with the Jets?
>> Yeah. Um, without, you know, giving too
much away, obviously, um, you know, be
the leader, you know, step in, you know,
be be the voice for him in the locker
room. Um, be myself first and foremost,
you know, and come in and, you know, be
the leader and take over, you know, and
take this thing over. And, um, you know,
he wants veteran leadership. uh he
wants, you know, guys who played a lot
of football and uh you know, I can be
both of those things for him. But, um,
you know, it's really simple. You know,
go out there, be yourself, lead the
team, uh, and go out there and get it
done and get wins and, you know, he's
going to be right there having have
having all of our backs and, um, you
know, I truly believe in co coach Glenn.
Um, I think he's a special coach and,
you know, I've seen him, I played
against him, I know what his defense has
to offer and so I know he's going to be
great on that side and uh, you know, I
can't wait to get back, you know, with
the team and and just get get to work.
Gino, did you feel connectivity right
off the bat when you and AG were having
those conversations? And did it take
long at all for you to be like, you know
what, this is where I got to go to?
>> I did, honestly, man. Just, you know,
because he's an ex player. I mean, I
watched him, you know, I'm growing up in
Miami. I watched him play against Dan
Marino. I watched him with the Jets, uh,
his his time there. And you know, when I
got to the league, um, he was actually
on the staff in in, uh, New York when I
got there. Um, and then following his
career, you know, him becoming the D
coordinator of the Saints and then
obviously, uh, going to be the D
coordinator in Detroit, having played
against him a few times, I know exactly
what again like what his defenses are
like, and they're always super tough.
They play sound. Um, he has a great
scheme, and I mean, guys just fly
around. And so, uh, knowing that that's
the type of coach that he is, that's the
type of defense that I want to play
alongside and play with, um, it was a
no-brainer. Again, um, he's a real dude.
Uh, he he talks to you. Uh, there's a
realness to him. There's a calmness to
him. Um, you know, there's a confidence
to him. And those are the things that,
you know, really draw me into it. You
mentioned it the other day when you were
talking to Joe Cena that your last
touchdown pass, you remember throwing it
to Quincy Nuna at Metife Stadium. With
that Yeah. But with that being said, how
much have you changed as a person and
also as a quarterback from the guy that
Jets fans saw throw that touchdown pass
to Q?
>> Well, you know, number one, as a person,
I think just growth, man. I mean I was
what was I like 25 years old maybe 26 at
the time and um I mean that's in a whole
10 years you know has gone by and um
that's a lot of experience and that
that's a lot of you know life lessons
and different things that you know will
kind of shape you and so I've gained a
ton of perspective just from my time
over over the course of time and um just
you know been been around some great
coaches been around some great players
um you know been on some great teams and
just being a sponge and learning
learning learning from all those
experiences I think has helped me uh get
to this point. But you never want to
stop learning. You never want to stop
growing. And so I'm continuing to learn
and uh this experience as well is one
that I will continue to learn from and
continue to be better from. And so just
as a man, I mean I got two kids now. Um
I'm a lot I'm a little bit older. Uh but
I still can move. I still can do all the
things that I was doing back then. Uh
and then as a player um you know again
just the mental side of it, right? just
understanding the understanding of the
game, the understanding of protections,
uh the understanding of, you know, Mike
points in the run game and just how to
get in and out of, you know, plays and,
you know, want to always be in a good
play. Um, those are the things again
that, you know, I've I've, you know,
quarterback top 10 offenses and I've
done certain things to me to me that can
show what I can do, but it's all about,
you know, what you can do right now. And
so, none of that stuff really matters.
I'm looking forward to my teammates. uh
there in Floren Park and and building
with those coaches and getting on the
field and and becoming what we'll become
uh you know once once everything starts
up.
>> I know the past like you said none of
that really matters and people are going
to have their own opinions but when you
go back to Seattle you became the
full-time starter in 22 to 24. You
accomplished a hell of a lot um during
that three-year run and you can look at
it statistically, you can look at it
from a win perspective. You can look at
it from clutch moments where you're
leading that team from behind. You can
look at it from the perspective of 2022,
you're the NFL comeback player of the
year. In 2022 and 23, you're a pro bowl
performer. Your passer ratings up uh
towards the top of the National Football
League or at the very top during that
run. not so much from Seahawks what they
were doing schematically but what was
happening for you to allow you to have
success
I think you know success is is
especially as a quarterback man like
it's not just simply on the quarterback
I can't just sit here and take all the
credit for that would be completely
wrong um first of all started with you
know having you know a great front
office who you know put the players
around me uh then you think think about
the coaches that we had you you know,
great coaches, Shane Waldron and, you
know, other coaches on our staff that
coached those guys up and prepared us
every single week. You know, the big
boys up front blocking for me. I
remember, you know, Charles Cross and
Abe Lucas, they're just rookies, you
know, that that first season. And so to
see those guys blossom into what they
are now, but just the big boys up front,
without them, nothing can go. Uh, then
you talk about the receivers on the
outside with DK, I had Tyler, I had
Jackson. Um all I mean tremendous
players you know running backs Ken
Walker, Charbanet uh just uh you know
surrounding with talent um you know
surrounding the quarterback with talent
and then allowing him to go out there
and play his game and uh that's what
happened. I just was able to go out
there and play free and um I had great
guys around me and obviously like I said
the experiences and all that stuff you
know helped me get to that point. Um but
the reality is is that I played
efficient you know I just went out there
and did my job. Um, I played alongside
my other teammates on offense and and
did what I was supposed to do. And then
when the moment came, whether that was a
clutch moment in the fourth quarter or a
big third down or time in the red zone,
that's when, you know, I was able to
step up and make a play. And that's what
the quarterback does, man. He's a part
of the team. And then, you know, if you
know, the best ones will always get you
over the hump. And so, for me, it was
always about just winning games, however
that looked. And I didn't care about
getting the credit. I still don't. Um,
statistics, you know, you want your
stats to be good because that means
you're playing good football. But
ultimately the only statistic that
matter is is wins. And so that's that's
all I'm focused on is just trying to you
know again you know build this thing
with my teammates and coaches build uh
you know just this this winning culture
that everyone can be proud of.
>> How can you grow from the adversity that
you faced last year? You know it better
than anybody as far as any pro is
concerned. Sometimes you're going to be
at the high point. Sometimes you're
going to endure some lows. But as far as
last year carrying it through to this
year, how can you grow from that?
>> Man, there was a ton of growth in last
season for me. I think um when I look
back on it,
that's what I can, you know, really hang
my hat on for last season is that I grew
in so many ways and I got better in so
many ways. Um we're still up what, 67%
completion. We're still high 60
completion percentage, close to 70. Um,
turnovers obviously was terrible last
year. Can't have that. And, you know, I
put that onus on myself. I'll never make
an excuse for that. I've got to, you
know, get that headed, you know, in the
right direction. And that's really what
I've been focusing on, studying film and
and working in the offseason with my
trainers to make sure that we eliminate
those things because the big plays, we
made a ton of big plays last year. We
were one of the most explosive, you
know, offenses for the first couple
weeks of the season. And then, you know,
we just kind of fell apart. And um
with that being said, I learned and I
grew and I stuck it out. And you know,
the guys who really held the rope until
the end because our team really did that
last year. Everyone held the rope. No
one was quitting on the team. Um
everyone was, you know, still coming
into the building and you know, giving
maximum effort because of the leadership
that we had on that team. Those are the
things that you can really hold on to.
And I believe that, you know, even
though the season didn't turn out the
way that I wanted it to, I still learned
from it and there's still going to be
things that I can use in the future. Um,
you know, from that season,
>> man, you sounded like a scout when you
were talking about the Jets personnel
offensively. What has you most excited
about this group?
>> Really just, man, just the opportunity
to play with those guys, to play
alongside those guys for so long. I
mean, I've been watching highlights of
Garrett Wilson routing dudes up. I'm
watching, you know, Breeze Hall run past
defenders in the, you know, in the
secondary and just make guys miss. And,
you know, it's cool to watch it on TV,
but, you know, now I get a chance to see
it, you know, live in, you know, in
person. And so, I I can't wait to get on
the field with those guys, just get to
practice, you know what I mean? just
start to build this thing and um you
know continue to work you know work the
way that I work but you know alongside
with my teammates and we can work
together you know the way that we uh the
connectedness that we have and the
camaraderie that we build um those are
the things that are going to pay off
when when you know Sunday comes and it's
a big third down or you know what I mean
it's it's a big fourth down that we got
to get or you know the game's on the
line you're going to look your brothers
in the eyes and they'll know that you
got them and they and and that they and
you'll know that they got you and uh you
go out there and you can be confident.
>> What about that offensive line who just
added one of your former teammates?
>> Man, uh heard so many great things
again. Um you know, still getting in
touch with the guys, but um just, you
know, looking forward to, you know,
standing back there and being their
quarterback um and connecting with those
guys and you know, developing a
brotherhood. Um you know, obviously uh
played with Dylan last year and I know
exactly who he is. I know he's a super
super tough guy. I mean, again, another
guy who showed up every single day, went
to work every single day despite the
record, despite whatever else was going
on. Uh, a true professional, and a guy
who's going to give you 110% every
single time. Those are the guys you want
to go to war with. And so, um, all those
guys on the front line, uh, you know,
again, I've heard so many great things
about him. I know we have some high
draft picks and some guys who've played
really well. And so, I look forward to,
you know, just being their quarterback
and and stepping into that huddle with
them. Um, that's that's the thing that,
you know, to me most important.
>> Gino, it wouldn't be fair to ask you
about what you guys are going to do in
schematically next year. You just
signed. I mean, you just came over via
trade from the Raiders, but you know who
your coordinator is in Frank Reich. just
just with the knowledge of his
experiences, not only as a player, but
as a coach and working with different
quarterbacks and then also knowing that
you're going to be working with Bill
Musgrave as well, a long time
quarterback coach in the NFL. Does that
get you amped up as well?
>> I'm super excited. Uh I got to meet co
coach Musgrave in the building. Uh had a
great talk, you know, with coach Reich.
Um and you know, again, just super
excited to be coached by those guys.
their track record really speaks for
itself. Um, you know, not much needs to
be said about that. I I just can't wait.
I mean, you know, I've had coaches, you
know, ex-coaches and people who know
them just texting and calling me like,
"You're going to love these guys.
They're quarterback guys. Uh, they
they've coached the best of the best."
And, uh, for me, just again to have this
opportunity, I'm really excited and very
grateful. You know, we talked about it
before to open up here that it seems
like yesterday for me that you were
drafted, but do you consider yourself a
young 35 as far as your career arc and
what's happened over the course of it?
>> Yeah, I would I would say so. You know,
obviously those years where, you know, I
was the backup, uh had a couple years
where I didn't take many hits and so um
you know, I guess those years are now on
the back end. You know what I mean? You
know, I can appreciate that. But I also
uh take care of my body, you know, my my
training regimen and my diet, you know,
all those things uh that I you know,
again, those are things that I that has
developed throughout my career as well.
But um you know, just understanding the
importance of of uh health um and mental
health as well. You know, just doing all
the little things to prepare yourself to
go out there and play well, you know, on
Sundays. And so, um yeah, I'm a young
36. I would say I have, you know, pretty
good genetics. My parents look pretty
young, but uh you know, I still work
extremely hard. Um it's not easy, but I
I put the work in and that's what gives
me the confidence.
>> What did it mean to you to get that text
from Deario that you alluded to before?
And also, you know, do you take like
responsibility, take pride in the
responsibility now that, hey, Deario's
coming back here? You sign a guy like
Minka Fitzpatrick who's done a lot of
great things in the National Football
League and say, "Hey, you know, we're
veterans who were brought here for a
reason to help the culture and help this
ship be turned around."
>> Oh yeah. Um, you know, again, Deario,
it seems like yesterday, you know, he
and I were, you know, young players, you
know, trying to find our way on the
Jets. And again, the way that this game
works, man, um we eventually went to
other places, but hey, we found our way
back and you know, the opportunity again
for us both to step back into that
building uh to to start to you know, try
and bond with our teammates and uh you
know, try and lead guys. That's what's
important, man. I mean, and that's what
this game is about, the camaraderie that
you build um with your teammates and
with guys throughout the league. Um, and
so yeah, Deario is a good friend of
mine. I remember us, you know, doing
Bible study at this house, you know,
when when we were both playing for the
Jets back then. And, uh, now we get
opportunity, you know, and and we're
super excited to be a part of this team.
And all of us, man, we're going to do
great things. I I, you know, I believe
it in my heart. Uh, but I can't wait to
get to work.
>> And finally, do you think you have
unfinished business here? And what kind
of message would you give the Jets fans
as you return to the green and white?
>> Oh, man. Unfinished business. Uh, you
know what? I think what we did in the
past, you know, that that was a time and
and now we're here. And I think you have
to be where your feet are. I think you
have to stay within the moment and and
focus on the, you know, what's right in
front of you. And so, yeah, I'm excited.
Uh, the past is the past. I really, my
mind hasn't really gone there. Um, I'm
focused on what we can do now here and
now. And uh for the fan base, you know,
I'm ready to again, you know, just dive
into the community and just get to meet
as many people as I can and try and help
as many people in in that community as I
can. Um, you know, my foundation has
been doing this since, you know, Seven
Sunday Heroes started back when I was,
you know, playing for the Jets back
then. And it's it's been a thing that
I've really, you know, um, focused on
throughout my career is the philanthropy
aspect of it. And uh you know I want to
be a part of the community and you know
the fan base is a part of the team.
They're you know a big part of the team.
So when when the opposing teams you know
come to Metife it's got to be rowdy.
It's got to be that old Jets feel where
you don't want to walk in there cuz you
know what I mean? You don't know what's
going to happen. They're in your ear.
They're being loud and then that defense
is out there swarming. Offense putting
up points and everybody's excited man.
That's what it's about. And so we want
to you know again cultivate that. We
want to cultivate great energy uh
throughout the organization and the fan
base and uh you know get everyone
excited about what's coming.
>> Uh Gino, thanks for your time today.
We're looking forward to having you back
up here in Floren Park, New Jersey
bound.
>> Thank you. I can't wait. Thanks for
having me.